A Guide to the Sandra McDonald, Holly Papers 1995-2000
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Sandra McDonald, Holly Papers 1995-2000
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
10553-an
ca. 485 items (2 Hollinger boxes; 1 Journal box)
This collection consists of papers pertaining to the four year tenure of Dr. Sandra F. McDonald as editor of the Holly Society Journal, 1995-2000, including copies of the sixteen journals that she edited during that time.
Sandra F. McDonald
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These papers were given by Dr. Sandra McDonald, Hampton, Virginia to the University of Virginia Library on February 9, 2000.
Scope and Content Information
This collection consists of papers pertaining to the four year tenure of Dr. Sandra F. McDonald as editor of the Holly Society Journal, 1995-2000, including copies of the sixteen journals that she edited during that time. Dr. McDonald has also given other papers concerning rhododendrons and the American Rhododendron Society to the Special Collections Department.
There are two main types of files: correspondence files with persons either submitting articles for publication to the Holly Society Journal or commenting on other writer's articles; and files devoted to individual numbers of the journal, including articles and correspondence. Also present are obituaries for Gene Eisenbeiss, Fred Galle, and David Leach.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically and chronologically.
Contents List
- Correspondence: Susyn Andrews 1997-2000, n.d. (Box 1)
- Correspondence: Charles R. Anderson 2000, n.d. (Box 1)
- Correspondence: Bonnie Lee Appleton 1997-1998, n.d. (Box 1)
- Correspondence: Barton M. Bauers, Sr. 1997-2000 (Box 1)
- Correspondence: Barton M. Bauers, Sr. re Controversy concerning Ilex Perado 2000 (Box 1)
- Correspondence: Barton M. Bauers, Sr. re his article "Description of Ilex x Attenuata Ex Ashe, F. Buxtonica Forma Nova 1997-2000, n.d. (Box 1)
- Correspodence: Barton M. Bauers, Sr. re his article "A New Forma of Ilex Intergra (Thunberg) ex J.A. Murray 1998-1999 (Box 1)
- Correspondence: Barton M. Bauers, Sr. re Questions and Answers Used 1996-1998 (Box 1)
- Correspondence: Betty Dickinson 1997 (Box 1)
- Correspondence: Ann Farnham 1997-2000 (Box 1)
- Correspondence: Eleanor K. Ford 1996-1997 (Box 1)
- Correspondence: Fred Galle 1997-1998, n.d. (Box 1)
- Correspondence: Kunso Kim 1997-1998 (Box 1)
- Correspondence: Virginia Morell 1997-1998 (Box 1)
- Correspondence: Richard Stalter 1997-2000, n.d. (Box 1)
- Correspondence: William Tancig 1998-2000, n.d. (Box 2)
- Correspondence: Timber Press, including McDonald's Review of Hollies: The Genus Ilex by Fred C. Galle 1997 (Box 2)
- Holly Society Journal Papers Volume 15, Numbers 1-4 1995-1997, n.d., 4 folders (Box 2)
- Holly Society Journal Papers Volume 16, Numbers 1 & 4 1997-1998, n.d., 2 folders (Box 2)
- Holly Society Journal Papers Volume 17, Number 1 1998-1999, n.d. (Box 2)
- Holly Society Journal Papers Volume 18, Numbers 1-4 1999-2000, n.d., 4 folders (Box 2)
- Holly Society Journal Articles Used 1998-1999, n.d. (Box 2)
- Obituaries of Gene Eisenbeiss, Fred Galle, and David Leach 1997-1998 (Box 2)
- Holly Society Journal(shelved with the American Rhododendron Society Chapter Newsletters) 1997-2000 (Box 3)